

DATA SCIENTIST · MATHEMATICAL ENGINEER

Santiago, Chile

□ (+56) 9 62475153 | ■ amvillalobos@uc.cl | ★ www.amvillalobos.com | • AdolfoVillalobos | • adolfovillalobos

Summary

Agrosuper S.A.

Current Site Reliability Engineer at start-up company Kasa. 7+ years experience specializing in the backend development, infrastructure automation, and computer hacking/security. Super nerd who loves Vim, Linux and OS X and enjoys to customize all of the development environment. Interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks, and learning new technologies and tools if the need arises.

Work Experience_

Santiago, Chile

LEAD DATA SCIENTIST AT JOINT VENTURE WITH INNOVATION GROUP

March. 2019 - June 2020

- Full ownership in developing a data-driven prototype to detect musculoskeletal disorders among slaughterhouse workers.
- Designed the measuring system using low-cost inertial sensors and Bluetooth protocols (2.0 and 4.0).
- Developed an SQL database for real time I/O operations using AWS.
- · Successfully implemented a machine learning pipeline based to predict dangerous behavior as a replacement for human screening.
- Results obtained were sent to a peer reviews journal.

Central Bank of Chile Santiago, Chile

DATA ANALYST INTERNSHIP AT THE FINANCIAL RESEARCH GROUP

Dec. 2017 - March. 2018

- Successfully got acquainted with state-of-the-art research on household debt modeling.
- · Implemented a game-theoretic matching algorithm to associate debt records from the SBIF with the Household Financial Survey (EFH).
- Proposed and implemented regression models in R and STATA to associate debt under-reporting by chilean households with debt-type and demographical information.
- · Successfully interacted with senior economists, balancing mathematical complexity with interpretability for monetary policy.
- Implemented a program to handle missing and corrupt data from the EFH survey.

Education

PUC (Pontificia Universidad Católica de Chile)

Santiago, Chile

B.S. IN MATHEMATICAL ENGINEERING

• Majored in deterministic modeling and delevoped

Mar. 2013 - Aug. 2018

[&]quot;Be the change that you want to see in the world."